(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
2023 Birthday Live Rosenthal
Start your Journey
#アキロゼ生誕祭2023
2023 Birthday Live Rosenthal
Start your Journey
#AkiroseBirthday2023
んなぁ～い！
Konlu-na!
えっと、席はこのあたりにいいならね。
Well, these seats should be good around here.
よっこいしょっと。
There we go.
今年もミュージカルテイストなのかな？
I wonder if it'll be a musical style again this year?
わくわく！
So exciting!
こんばんドドド！
Good evening-dodo-dodo!
ここ座ってもいい？
Can I sit here?
やや、お揃いで。
Oh, you're all here.
よいしょ。
There we go.
今日はアキロゼの誕生日だから、一緒に祝ってやろうじゃないか。うんうん。
Since it's Akirose's birthday today, let's celebrate together. Yes, yes.
ヤッホー！
Hello!
あ、そういえばアキロゼ先輩誕生日前にスプラに全然インしてなかったんだよね。
Oh, come to think of it, Akirose-senpai wasn't on Splatoon at all before her birthday.
練習頑張ってたってことだから、楽しみだね。
That means she was practicing hard, so I'm looking forward to it.
お、暗室のバカタレ共。よお揃いで。
Oh, the fools in the dark. You're all together.
いやいや、今日はポルカも出るから応援しててな。うんうん。
No, no, Polka is appearing today too, so please cheer me on. Yes, yes.
頑張れポルカ～！
Go for it, Polka~!
いや、ロボ子さん？
Wait, Roboco-san?
あんたも出る側でしょうが。
You're on the performing side too.
待機所ここじゃないから。
The waiting room isn't here.
はっ！ボボンガボン！
Huh? Bobon-ga-bon!
はぁ、行ったな。
Hah, they're gone.
行ったね。
They sure are.
もうすぐ始まりそうだけど間に合うかな？
It's about to start, I wonder if they'll make it?
まったく、ごちゃごちゃ煩いのら。
Honestly, they're so noisy.
我々は楽しませてもらうだけなののよ。
We're just here to enjoy ourselves.
うっす！
Yes!
akirose
AKIROSE Birthday Live
LET'S HAVE FUN!
CAST
アーニャ・メルフィッサ
Anya Melfissa
こぼ・かなえる
Kobo Kanaeru
がうる・ぐら
Gawr Gura
ハコス・ベールズ
Hakos Baelz
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
ロボ子さん
Robocosan
獅白ぼたん
Shishiro Botan
博衣こより
Hakui Koyori
森カリオペ
Mori Calliope
アキ・ローゼンタール
Aki Rosenthal
Start your Journey
あるところにドロシーという少女がおりました。
Once upon a time, there was a girl named Dorothy.
幼い頃に両親を亡くしたドロシーは
She's lost her parents by death when innocent infant
叔父と叔母との退屈な生活に飽き飽きしていました。
and gets weary of life with her aunt and uncle, too ordinary.
いつしか彼女は夢見ていたのです。
This lovable girl is dreaming of adventure,
不思議の国で冒険する自分の姿を...
in an extraordinary Wonderland.
Music Wizard of OZ
by OSTER project
果てしなく広がるこの空の下
Under this sky that expands endlessly
僕らを導くのはあのメロディ
What leads us is that melody
遥かなる時間を超えて繋がる
Connecting across far-off time
どんな時も心は覚えているから
Because the heart remembers no matter when
いつものように目が覚めると
When I wake up just like usual
いつものようにニワトリに餌をあげるの
I feed the chickens just like usual
いつものように焦げたトーストと
With burnt toast just like usual
いつものようにおばさんガミガミおじさんブツブツもう沢山よ
With auntie nagging and uncle grumbling just like usual, I've had enough!
あぁ...私だっていつか
Ah... I too, someday
絵本みたいな冒険してみたいな
Want to try having an adventure like in a picture book
悪い魔女とか魔法使いとか
Evil witches or wizards and such
考えるだけでゾクゾクしちゃう
Just thinking about it gives me chills
あぁ...このままどこかへ飛んでゆきたいわ
Ah... I want to fly away somewhere just like this
竜巻とかで
With a tornado or something
Music Wizard of OZ
きゃああ！
Kyaaa!
悲しみは　笑いましょう
Let's laugh at our sadness
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？
作詞：木村トモトカ　作曲：酒井リョウスケ　編曲：小池一也
Shall We Dance?
Lyrics: Kimura Tomotoka  Composition: Sakai Ryosuke  Arrangement: Koike Kazuya
生きるって　マリオネット
Life is like a marionette
心臓が　スイングしたら
If your heart begins to swing
今宵はいかが
How about tonight?
ア・トゥ・ドゥ　ア・トゥ・ドゥ
A tout doux, a tout doux
ア・トゥ・ドゥ・ドゥ・シャ
A tout doux, doux chat
私うまく踊れないわ
I can't dance very well
痛みも恨みも悲しみも
Pain, resentment, and sadness too
混ぜて　混ぜて
Mix them, mix them
こねて　こねて
Knead them, knead them
おやすみのキス
A goodnight kiss
Shall we dance?　踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望　欲望　This is our life
Despair, desire, this is our life
Shadow life　余計なこと
Shadow life, don't think
考えないで一つになりましょう
about unnecessary things, let's become one
イナイ　イナイ　イナイ
Gone, gone, gone
イナイ
Gone
人間って　人間って
Humans are, humans are
イイナ
Wonderful
ランラン　ランラランララン...
Lan lan, lan la lan la lan...
泣きたいのに　笑っちゃう
I want to cry, but I end up laughing
人生って　ピエロ
Life is like a clown
本当の　心隠して
Hiding my true heart
笑うふりしてるの
Pretending to smile
ア・トゥ・ドゥ　ア・トゥ・ドゥ
A tout doux, a tout doux
ア・トゥ・ドゥ・ドゥ・シャ
A tout doux, doux chat
私うまく生きれないわ
I can't live very well
本音も嘘も不安も
True feelings, lies, and anxiety too
溶かして　溶かして
Melt them, melt them
蓋して　蓋して
Cover them, cover them
おやすみなさい
Goodnight
Shall we dream?　夢見ましょう
Shall we dream? Let's dream
寝ても覚めても　This is our life
Asleep or awake, this is our life
Shadow life　目を閉じて
Shadow life, close your eyes
嫌なこと全部　忘れましょう
And let's forget all the bad things
Shall we dance?　不器用でも
Shall we dance? Even if you're clumsy
足掻いて　掻いて　This is our life
Struggle and scratch, this is our life
Shadow step　余計なこと
Shadow step, don't think
考えないで手を鳴らせ
about unnecessary things, clap your hands
Shall we smile?　今だけは
Shall we smile? For now at least
一緒に笑ってみませんか
Won't you try laughing with me?
Shadow dance　今だけは
Shadow dance, for now at least
全部忘れて一緒に飛びましょう
Forget everything and let's jump together
Shall we dance?　踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望　欲望　This is our life
Despair, desire, this is our life
Shadow life　余計なこと
Shadow life, don't think
考えないで一つになりましょう
about unnecessary things, let's become one
イナイ　イナイ　イナイ
Gone, gone, gone
イナイ
Gone
人間って　人間って
Humans are, humans are
イイナ
Wonderful
イナイ　イナイ
Gone, gone
人間って　人間って
Humans are, humans are
イイナ
Wonderful
ランラン　ランラランララン...
Lan lan, lan la lan la lan...
Music Wizard of OZ
信じられない
Unbelievable!
今日はおめでとう
Congratulations today!
東の魔女が死んだ
The Wicked Witch of the East is dead
死んだ
Dead
意地悪で怖い魔女
The mean and scary witch
誰も逆らいやしない
Nobody dare oppose her
隣の国の王子様も
Even the prince of the neighboring kingdom
カエルに変えられたっけな
Was turned into a frog, wasn't he?
だけど突然飛んできた
But then suddenly, flying in
家に潰されたのさ
She was crushed by a house
これじゃ魔法も使い果たしさ
Now her magic is all used up
東の魔女は死んだ
The Wicked Witch of the East is dead
竜巻にのって飛んできただけさ
I just came flying in on a tornado
風の魔法使いに祝福を
Blessings to the Wizard of the Wind
一体ここはどこなんだろう
I wonder where on earth I am
彗星みたいボクら
We are like comets
何でも叶える旅をプレゼント
Gifting you a journey where any wish comes true
あの道を辿って
Follow that road
エメラルドの街へ
To the Emerald City
さあ Music Wizard of Oz もとへ
Now, to the Music Wizard of Oz
何やら迷い込んだ世界で始まる冒険
An adventure begins in this mysterious world I've wandered into
鍵盤の道を辿って
Follow the piano key road
エメラルドの街へ行こう
Let's go to the Emerald City
突然現れたカカシが歌い出す
A scarecrow suddenly appears and starts to sing
みんながオイラを馬鹿にするのさ
Everyone makes a fool out of me
悩みがあるのなら聞いてあげるわ
If you have troubles, I'll listen to them
何が？ 今日はいいお天気ですね
What? It's a lovely day today, isn't it?
散歩歩けば忘れちまう
Once I take a walk, I forget everything
知恵を持ってないカカシなのさ
I'm a scarecrow who has no brains
おかげでおいらは笑い草
Thanks to that, I'm a laughingstock
いかれた案山子さ
I'm a crazy scarecrow
間抜けな知恵の無さ隠すな
Don't hide your silly lack of brains
旅をすれば見つかるはず
If you go on a journey, you're bound to find some
それなら一緒に知恵を探しに行こう
In that case, let's go find some brains together
あの道を辿って
Follow that road
さあ Music Wizard of Oz もとへ
Now, to the Music Wizard of Oz
お願い事は何？
What is your wish?
もちろん賢い知恵のさ
Some clever brains, of course
さあ足取り軽やかに
Come, with a light step
エメラルドの街へ行こう
Let's go to the Emerald City
突然現れたブリキのロボット
A tin robot suddenly appears
油を差したらゆっくり踊りだして
When oiled, it starts to dance slowly
目から錆びた涙
Rusty tears from its eyes
フラフラされたダンスなら完璧に踊っているのに
Though I can dance a wobbly dance perfectly
あなたのダンスにはハートがないって言われるの
They tell me my dance has no heart
デジタルの檻の中
Inside a digital cage
与えられた言葉だけじゃわからないことばかり
Only given words, there's so much I don't understand
嬉しい 悲しい 楽しい
Happy, sad, fun
それなら一緒に探しに行こう 君のココロ
In that case, let's go find it together—your heart
何だって願いを叶えてくれる不思議な Music Wizard
The mysterious Music Wizard who grants any wish
デジタルの檻の外
Outside the digital cage
鮮やかに彩る光
Vividly colored lights
この胸で感じたい 本物の私をみつけたい
I want to feel it in my chest—I want to find the real me
あの道を辿って
Follow that road
The Music Wizard of Oz もとへ
To the Music Wizard of Oz
お願いごとは なに？
What is your wish?
賢いズノーが 宝物さ
A clever brain is my treasure.
ゆたかなハートが 宝物さ
A rich heart is my treasure.
さぁ 歌声 高らかに
Now, let's sing out loud,
エメラルドの 街へ ゆこう
and head to the Emerald City.
ライオンだ！
It's a lion!
ガオー！
Roar!
お月を見てる
Looking at the moon.
フガッ！
Snort!
ガオー！
Roar!
きいてくれ 俺たちの 悲しい ものがたり
Listen to our sad story.
きいてくれ わたしたちの 悲しい ものがたり
ライオンなのに
Even though I'm a lion...
お肉が こわくて たべられない
I'm afraid of meat and can't eat it.
えー！
What!
きょうも かりへ いくのさ
Today too, I'm going hunting.
キャベツ 人参 ブロッコリー レタスに トマト
Cabbage, carrots, broccoli, lettuce, and tomatoes.
いっぱな キバは あるのみ
I only have these fine fangs.
うまれて このかた ベジタリアン
I've been a vegetarian since the day I was born.
あさごはん
Breakfast.
ゴマサラダ
Sesame salad.
ひるごはん
Lunch.
ポテトサラダ
Potato salad.
ばんごはん
Dinner.
サン！バー！グ！
Sun! Burger!
中身はもちろん豆腐
The inside is, of course, tofu.
うまそー
Looks yummy.
だけど ともだちに は
But for my friends...
ばかに されているんだ
...I'm being made fun of.
ゆうきだして お肉も
I want to be brave and...
たべてみたい
...try eating meat too.
それなら ゆうきを
In that case, courage...
さがしに ゆこう
...let's go find it.
そしたら きっと たべられる
If we do that, surely we'll be able to eat...
牛肉も
...beef too.
ぶたにくも
Pork too.
とりにくも
Chicken too.
そして かりへ いくのさ
And then, let's go hunting.
焼肉 しゃぶしゃぶ 親子丼 ジビエに ステーキ
Grilled meat, shabu-shabu, chicken and egg bowl, wild game, and steak.
花ざかりメニュー 美味そうで
The blooming menu looks delicious, so...
旅に出るのさ
...let's set out on a journey.
あの みちを たどって
Follow that path.
さぁ ミュージック ウィザード の もとへ
Now, to the Music Wizard.
お願いごとは なに？
What is your wish?
ズノーさ
A brain.
ココロさ
A heart.
ユウキさ
Courage.
旅路さ
A journey.
さぁ みんな 手を取り合って
Now everyone, take each other's hands,
エメラルドの 街へ ゆこう
and let's go to the Emerald City.
Loneliness, you're tied around my wrist
When all I ever wanted was this
Yeah, all I ever wanted was this
Sleepless nights, always seem to lose these fights
Building up my thoughts like bricks
But nothing in my blood says quit
When the lights go out
And I'm all by myself in the darkness
I hear my heart beating the hardest
Oh, I was born to break these chains
Like a spark before the flames
Watch me light a fire, fire in my soul
Yeah, I can feel it in my bones
Like a dream ready to explode
Watch me light a fire
Battle scars, lead me through the night like stars
And all I ever wanted was this
Yeah, all I ever wanted was this
Out of bounds, when every single wall comes down
I'll be standing on the edge of greatness
Oh, I was born to break these chains
Like a spark before the flames
Watch me light a fire, fire in my soul
Yeah, I can feel it in my bones
Like a dream ready to explode
Watch me light a fire, fire in my soul
Fire, fire, fire, fire, fire, fire
Watch me light a fire,
fire in my soul
fire fire fire fire fire fire
Watch me light a fire
When the lights go out
And I'm all by myself in the darkness
I hear my heart beating the hardest
Oh, I was born to break these chains
Like a spark before the flames
Watch me light a fire
Yeah, I can feel it in my bones
Like a dream ready to explode
Watch me light a fire, fire in my soul
fire fire fire fire fire fire
Watch me light a fire,
fire in my soul
fire fire fire fire fire fire
Watch me light a fire
照らし出して グリーンライツ
Shine out, Green-Lights
広がる未来を
The spreading future
きっと いつか 君を照らすまで
Until it surely shines on you someday
グリーンライツ・セレナーデ
作詞・作曲・編曲 Omoi
Green-Lights Serenade
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Omoi
改めて言うことでもないけど
It's not something I need to say again, but
今だからこそ言わせて
Let me say it now because it's the present
あの日君が見つけてくれること
That you would find me on that day
なんとなく予感してたんだ
I had a feeling somehow
走り出した 君にもっと 力をあげたくて
I wanted to give more strength to you who started running
ずっと 前に 心決めたんだ
I made up my mind a long time ago
照らし出して グリーンライツ はるか未来を
Shine out, Green-Lights, on the far future
きっと いつか 君を照らすまで
Until it surely shines on you someday
今までも いつまでも 隣にいたいのは
The reason I want to be by your side now and forever
輝いた君の顔を 間近で見たいから
Is because I want to see your shining face up close
言葉時々に無力で なかなか
Words are sometimes powerless, and
この世界は変わらないけど
This world doesn't change easily, but
もし君が持ってる その魔法で
If with that magic you possess
新しい世界を作れるとしたら
You could create a new world
なんてね 言ってみただけ そんなの
Just kidding, I just said it, such a thing
本当できるわけない わけがないでしょう
There's no way it's really possible, right?
いいよもっと 信じてよ 何度転んでも
It's okay, believe more, no matter how many times you fall
君は 君の やり方でいいのだ
You're fine just the way you are
照らし出して グリーンライツ 立ち向かう未来を
Shine out, Green-Lights, on the future you face
きっと いつか 君を照らすまで
Until it surely shines on you someday
堪えきれない夜に 窓辺で泣いていいよ
You can cry by the window on nights you can't bear
また晴れた日に 見せ合う 嬉し涙を
Let's show each other our happy tears on another sunny day
走り出した 君にもっと 力をあげたくて
I wanted to give more strength to you who started running
ずっと 前に 心決めたんだ
I made up my mind a long time ago
照らし出して グリーンライツ はるか未来を
Shine out, Green-Lights, on the far future
きっと いつか 君を照らすまで
Until it surely shines on you someday
振り返ると遠く 手を振ってくれる君も
You, who waves from afar when looking back
この先のどこかで 出会える君も
And you, who I will meet somewhere ahead
誰にも真似できない あなたを抱きしめて
Embracing you, whom no one else can imitate
虹色と輝き 間近で見たい
I want to see the rainbow-colored radiance up close
ラーーー！
Laaa!
エメラルルド、ようこそエメラルルドの街へ
Emerald, welcome to the city of Emerald.
眩い光の街へ
To the city of dazzling light,
全てが輝き放つエメラルルド
where everything shines, Emerald.
さあ、そしてこの私がエメラルドのミュージックで
Now, and I, with Emerald's music,
奇跡を巻き起こす、エメラルルド
will stir up miracles, Emerald.
エメラルドのピアノ
The Emerald piano.
エメラルドのサックスを
The Emerald saxophone.
エメラルドのギター
The Emerald guitar.
エメラルドのドラムを
The Emerald drums.
何一つ欠けてちゃ、奇跡は起こせないの
If even one is missing, miracles cannot happen.
何一つ欠けてちゃ、ウィザードになれない
If even one is missing, I cannot become a wizard.
澄まされた、あの旋律が叫んでいる
That refined melody is crying out,
不完全な奇跡の街
in the city of incomplete miracles.
お願いよ誰か取り戻して、西の魔女から
Please, someone take back from the Witch of the West,
魔法のギターを
the magical guitar.
La la la... 私たちが
La la la... We will
知恵を絞って
rack our brains,
勇気を出して
summon our courage,
あの魔法のギターを取り戻すため
and take back that magical guitar.
逃げろ、逃げろ
Run away, run away,
竜巻に乗って行こう
let's go on a tornado.
西の砦に鳴り響くミュージック
Music echoing in the fortress of the West.
憂いを映した、孤独なギター
The lonely guitar, reflecting sorrow.
Alone without you,
独りきりのコンサート
a solo concert.
誰も聴いちゃいないのさ
No one is listening.
美しい音色奏でているのに
Even though I'm playing a beautiful tone.
分かち合えないものに意味などあるものか
What meaning is there in things that cannot be shared?
So please listen to my sounds.
それなら
In that case,
僕たちと一緒に
come with us!
友達を探しに
To find some friends.
行こうよミュージックウィザードの元へ
Let's go to the Music Wizard.
独りでは奇跡は起こせないから
Because miracles can't be made alone.
皆で行こう
Let's all go together!
エメラルルドの街へ
To the city of Emerald.
さあ、魔法のギターで
Now, with the magical guitar,
僕らの世界を輝かせています
our world is being made to shine.
ほら耳を澄ませば、聞こえるでしょう
Look, if you listen closely, you can hear it, right?
誰の中にも、隠れてる魔法
The magic hidden inside everyone.
誰もが生まれ持った喜びを
The joy that everyone was born with,
さあ呼び覚まして
now, awaken it.
答えはそこにあるの
The answer is right there.
思いを歌にできるのは
Being able to turn thoughts into song,
僕らが知恵を持っているから
is because we have wisdom.
好きな歌を口ずさむと
Humming a favorite song,
ワクワクするの
makes me feel excited.
...はず　心が動くから
...it must be because my heart is moved.
心を持ってるから
Because I have a heart.
大きな声をあげて歌を歌えるのは
The reason we can sing with loud voices
僕らが勇気を持っているから
Is because we have courage.
そして声を合わせて
And joining our voices,
喜びを分かち合える
we can share our joy.
それが友達
That is what friends are.
ありのままの自分の中に
Within your true self,
生きづいてる大切なもの
the precious thing that's alive.
拾い上げて
Pick it up,
気付かせてくれる
and let me realize it.
それが奇跡
That is a miracle,
それがMUSIC
that is MUSIC.
最後はあなたの願いを聞かせて
Finally, let me hear your wish.
思いのままに夢を描いて
Draw your dreams as you please.
ねぇ、
Hey,
私気づいたの
I realized it.
ワクワクする冒険よりも
More than a thrilling adventure,
どんな素晴らしい夢よりも
more than any wonderful dream,
かけがえのないものがあるの
there's something irreplaceable.
憎たらしくなるときもあるけど
Even though there are times I get annoyed,
私の願いはただ一つ
my wish is just one.
家族に会いたい
I want to see my family.
あなたの愛したあの歌を
That song you loved,
あなたの愛するあの人も
that person you love,
きっとどこかで口ずさんでるから
must be humming it somewhere.
耳を澄まして
Listen closely.
私の愛するこの歌が
This song I love,
私の愛するあの人と
with that person I love,
私をいつでも繋ぎ合わせてくれる
will always keep us connected.
魔法の絆
A magical bond.
果てしなく広がるこの空の下
Under this infinitely spreading sky,
僕らを導くのは
what guides us
あのメロディ
is that melody.
はるかなる時間を超えてつながる
Connecting across vast stretches of time,
どんな時も心は覚えているよ
my heart remembers, no matter when.
奇跡のMUSIC
Miraculous MUSIC.
「あら、気づいちゃいました？」
"Oh, did you notice?"
生まれて30秒で最初に聞いた言葉は
The first words I heard 30 seconds after birth
当たり前、そりゃ覚えてないけど嬉しかったはず
Of course I don't remember, but I must've been happy.
今でもだいたいのことは変わってないというか
Even now, most things haven't changed, or rather,
中身は変わっていませんのでその辺でも評価お願い
my heart hasn't changed, so please rate me on that.
携帯のアンテナを光らせた
I made the phone's antenna glow,
それが超キュートなあの子だって知っていたり
knowing that she's that super cute girl.
っていうかアンテナって何言っているのよ
I mean, what are you talking about, 'antenna'?
なんか私に付き合ってくれるの好き
I like how you somehow go along with me.
逆にどこ？私のどこが好き？
Where? What do you like about me, exactly?
ねぇねぇねぇ
Hey, hey, hey.
私の一番かわいいところに気づいてる？
Have you noticed my most adorable side?
そんな君が一番すごい！すごい！
You, who notices that, are the best! The best!
すごすぎる
So amazing!
そして君が知ってる 私が一番可愛いの
And you know that I'm the cutest.
私もそれに気づいた
I've realized that too.
だから それ可愛い あれ可愛いなんて
So, saying that this is cute or that is cute...
誰可愛い それ可愛いなんて
Don't say that anyone or anything else is cute.
言わないで 私以外なんてやだ
Don't say it. I don't want anyone but me.
なんて ありえない
That's impossible.
私 気づいちゃいました
I just realized.
毎日何十回 褒められまくったお菓子は
Sweets that get praised dozens of times a day...
昨日よりちょっと甘くなるって 前に聞いたような
I think I heard they get a bit sweeter than yesterday.
さすがにそれ なんか変だけど 私は言われたいタイプでして
That's a bit strange, but I'm the type who wants to be told that.
もっと分かりやすくていいんだよ お待ちしてます お願い
It's okay to be more obvious. I'm waiting for it, please.
何してても どんな顔見せてても
No matter what I'm doing or what face I'm making...
いつも超キュートだって 確信してるのは
The reason I'm so sure I'm always super cute is...
なんだかさ 知らなかったタイプの運命のトビラ
Because of a type of door to destiny I never knew.
見合ったりは無理 ごめん 逆にでも それより楽しいよ
I can't look at you directly, sorry. But conversely, this is more fun.
ねえ ねえ ねえ！
Hey, hey, hey!
私の1番可愛いところをよく見てる
You're looking closely at my cutest part.
そんな君が本当に超ラッキーな人すぎる
A person like you is truly way too lucky.
そして君が何だって 想い合えるように
So that we can love each other no matter what.
私はそれに気づいた
I've realized that.
会えない時も どんな表情してるかとか
Even when we can't meet, I wonder what expression you're making.
気持ち悪いくらい 想像しちゃうから
Because I imagine it to a point that's almost creepy.
それ可愛い あれ可愛いよって
Say "that's cute," "this is cute."
本当に可愛いって言って
Say it's really cute.
私の1番可愛いところに気づいてる
You've noticed my cutest part.
そんな君が1番すごいすごいよ すごすぎる
You're the most amazing, amazing! So amazing!
そして君が知ってる 私が一番可愛いの
And you know that I'm the cutest.
私はそれに気づいた
I've realized that.
私の1番可愛いところをよく見てる
You're looking closely at my cutest part.
そんな君が本当に超ラッキーな人すぎる
A person like you is truly way too lucky.
そして君が何だって 想い合えるように
So that we can love each other no matter what.
私はそれに気づいた
I've realized that.
私の1番可愛いところに気づいてる
You've noticed my cutest part.
そんな君が1番すごいすごいよ すごすぎる
You're the most amazing, amazing! So amazing!
そして君が知ってる 私が一番可愛いの
And you know that I'm the cutest.
私もそれに気づいた
I've realized that too.
だから それ可愛い あれ可愛いなんて
So, saying that this is cute or that is cute...
誰可愛い それ可愛いなんて
Don't say that anyone or anything else is cute.
言わないで 私以外なんてやだ
Don't say it. I don't want anyone but me.
なんて ありえない
That's impossible.
アキロゼ生誕祭2023を見てくれてるみんな！
Everyone watching the Akirose Birthday Festival 2023!
見えてる？聞こえてる？
Can you see me? Can you hear me?
アローナ！
Alona!
はぁ〜 やっと喋れる〜
I can finally talk!
もう... 今回盛りだくさんだったね
There was so much in it this time, wasn't there?
ということで、今回のライブは
So, for this live performance...
昨年に引き続きまして
Following on from last year,
大好きなオトスタプロジェクトさんの
from the beloved Otosta Project,
『オズの魔法使い』のミュージカルを
a musical of "The Wizard of Oz"
やらせていただきました！
I performed it for you!
素敵な曲をありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for the wonderful songs!
そして、今回のライブにぴったりな
And perfect for this live performance,
ステージセットを こんなに可愛く作ってもらいました！
the stage set was made so cute like this!
めっちゃ可愛いでしょ？
It's super cute, right?
ぜひね、アーカイブとかでも
Please, even in the archive,
じっくり色んなところ見てくれたら
take a good look at all the details.
めちゃくちゃ制作陣も喜びます！
The production team will be so happy!
もちろん、アキロゼも喜びます！
And of course, Akirose will be happy too!
ぜひね、そんな感想とかもいっぱい見たいので
I really want to see all your thoughts and comments.
今日の配信の感想や、可愛いスクショ
Comments on today's stream, cute screenshots,
短い動画とか、GIF、ギフ？などなど
short videos, GIFs, and so on.
ハッシュタグをつけていっぱいツイートしてください！
Please tweet a lot with the hashtag!
アキロゼめっちゃ巡回します！見ます！よろしくね！
Akirose will be checking them all out! I'll see them! Thanks!
このハッシュタグはこちら！
The hashtag is right here!
これ付けると見やすいので、ぜひぜひ付けてください！
It makes them easy to find, so please use it!
YouTubeのコメントもよろしくね〜！
And please leave comments on YouTube too!
一呼吸ついたところで
Now that I've caught my breath...
ここで...
Right here...
重大発表！イェーイ！
A major announcement! Yay!
なんと
Guess what?
アキ・ローゼンタール
Aki Rosenthal's...
オリジナル曲第4弾発売決定！
4th original song release decided!
それでは
And now...
先行お披露目しちゃいます
I'll be doing a pre-release performance.
聞いてください
Please listen.
キミにまつわる運命事情
The Destiny Surrounding You
今日は絶好調 そのはずでしたか コケッ
I was in top form today, or so I thought... *trip*
天気予報ド外れ
The weather forecast was way off
ドア閉まるバス
The bus doors closed
憂鬱マンデー
Melancholy Monday
なんて不条理
How absurd
文句誰行き
Who should I complain to?
八つ当たりは問題外
Taking it out on others is out of the question
どうしようもないコト 多すぎエブリデイ
Too many helpless things every day
現実は手強い
Reality is tough
だけど試練の向こうへ
But beyond the trials
ため息ついてここから
Taking a sigh, from here
立ち上がれたらまた
If I can stand up again
なにかが始まる
Something will begin
Let's get it going now, going now!
がむしゃら君に
To the reckless you
どこへだって繰り出して
Going out anywhere
胸張って楽しんじゃおう
Be proud and let's have fun
Up and Down!
Say everyone!
Going now, going now!
蹴散らしちゃえよ
Kick it all away
波乱万丈
Stormy life
大体の運命
Most of destiny
変えていくのは自分だって
Is something you can change yourself
キミを知ってる
I know you
電車で割り込み
Cutting in line on the train
コンビニで傘無くなった
Lost my umbrella at the convenience store
チリチリ減ってってる ハートの残機
My heart's remaining lives are dwindling
あとどれくらい？
How much is left?
辻褄合ってなくていい
It's okay if it doesn't make sense
悲劇の１秒先で
One second past the tragedy
思い切り笑ったら
If you laugh with all your might
いい日に格上げ！
It's upgraded to a good day!
Let's get it going now, going now!
顔上げてほら
Lift your head, look
ありのままのステップで
With your natural steps
予測不能 未来へ踏み出して
Stepping into the unpredictable future
Say everyone!
Going now, going now!
吹き飛ばしちゃえ
Blow it all away
冴えない 浮かばない 顔した
Looking dull and listless
今日なんて全部
Today is everything
自分だけがそう出来るって
Only you can do it
キミは知ってる
You know it
I will try it again! 分かってるはずさ
I will try it again! You should know
I will try it again! 拓かれるはずさ
I will try it again! It should open up
今はまだ遠い そんな景色
That scenery is still far away now
困っても 眩しくて
Even if you're troubled, it's dazzling
この手で掴めるまで...
Until I can grab it with these hands...
Let's get it going now, going now!
がむしゃら君に
To the reckless you
どこへだって繰り出して
Going out anywhere
胸張って楽しんじゃおう
Be proud and let's have fun
Up and Down!
Say everyone!
めげない！
Don't falter!
挫けない！
Don't get discouraged!
あきらめないで！
Don't give up!
波乱万丈
Stormy life
大体の運命
Most of destiny
変えていくのは自分
Is something you change yourself
さあ どうするんだ
Now, what will you do?
ハッピーチューンの奏で方
How to play a happy tune
キミは知ってる
You know it
キミにまつわる運命事情でしたー！
That was "The Destiny Surrounding You"!
どうだったかな？はーい！
How was it? Yes!
こちらの新曲は今後各種ストリーミングサービスで配信が決定してます！
This new song is scheduled to be released on various streaming services!
本日の生誕祭では先行お披露目ということで、今後の発売日は...
Since today was a pre-release performance, the future release date...
Twitterなどで案内するので楽しみにしててね！
Will be announced on Twitter and such, so look forward to it!
こちらの新曲はライブタイトルにもなっている...
This new song is also the title of this live concert...
Start your journey
あなたの旅を始めよう
Let's start your journey.
そんなふうに背中を押してくれるような曲になっています。
It's a song meant to give you that extra push.
元気が欲しい時、
When you need some energy,
テンション上げたい時とかにいっぱいきいてもらって、
or when you want to get hyped up, please listen to it a lot,
勇気を出してくれたら嬉しいなと思います。
and I'll be happy if it helps you find your courage.
あ、Twitterでさっきお知らせするって言ったんだけど、
Oh, I mentioned earlier I'd post an announcement on Twitter,
うわー！
Whoa!
もうTwitterフォローしてる...
You're already following me on Twitter...
よね？
Right?
してないやつ、いいねえおなー！
If you aren't, you better go do it now!
チャンネル登録してないやつ、
For those not subscribed to the channel,
いいねえおなー！
You better go do it now!
今今まだのひと今よ！
If you haven't yet, now's the time!
はい、
Alright,
曲の感想とかも、
about your thoughts on the song,
Twitterでね、ハッシュタグをつけて聞かせてもらえると
if you share them on Twitter with the hashtag,
アキも見やすいのでよろしくお願いします。
it makes it easier for me to find them. Thank you!
そして、
And now,
お待ちかねの、
what you've all been waiting for,
グッズ紹介だー！
the merchandise introduction!
アキロゼ 生誕祭 2023 5月27日販売開始
Aki Rosenthal Birthday Festival 2023 On sale starting May 27th
アキロゼ生誕祭2023グッズが発売になります！
Aki Rosenthal's Birthday 2023 goods are going on sale!
ライブテーマの「Start your journey あなたの旅を始めよう」という思いを
The theme of the live concert, "Start your journey," is
ぎゅっと込めた、
tightly packed into these,
オズの魔法使いをイメージしたグッズになっています！
and the designs are inspired by "The Wizard of Oz"!
内容は、
The lineup includes the
Start your journey ポップアップアクリルスタンド。
"Start your journey" pop-up acrylic stand.
こちらじゅん先生の描き下ろしになっています！
This features a new illustration by Jun-sensei!
めちゃめちゃ可愛くて、ロゼ隊も、
It's super cute, and it also features Rosetai,
ジョブズも、嫉妬するペンギンもちゃっかり、
Jobs, and even the jealous penguin,
旅の仲間と加わってるので、
as fellow companions on the journey.
ぜひ飾って楽しんでもらえたらと思います。
I hope you enjoy displaying it.
そして、
And then,
持ってお出かけ、そのまま旅に出れちゃう、
you can take this with you on a real journey:
ブック型ポーチ！
the book-type pouch!
そして普段使いから、
Plus, from everyday use
ご褒美使いまでできる、
to special occasions,
りんご型プレートとカトラリーセットも
the apple-shaped plate and cutlery set
一緒になっています。
are also included.
ぜひお家でもお外でも楽しんでください。
Please enjoy them both at home and outdoors.
そして今回は、
And this time,
シチュエーションボイス。
we have situation voices.
「もしもアキロゼと温泉デートに行ったら」
"What if you went on a hot spring date with Akirose?"
そしてASMRボイスもあります！
And there's also an ASMR voice!
こちらみんなのことを思ってね、ドキドキできるような、
I made these thinking of all of you. It's a heart-pounding
シチュエーションボイスドラマになってるので、
situation voice drama, so
ぜひそっちも楽しみにしててください。
please look forward to that as well.
そしてこちら、
And for this one,
なんと、
unbelievably,
フルセット購入の方は、
those who purchase the full set
アキロゼ直筆の
will receive a
サインが
handwritten signature
プロマイドチェキに書かれて届いちゃう、えー！？
on a bromide cheki card. What?!
はい、アキロゼ書きます！
Yes, I'll be signing them myself!
直筆サイン、
A handwritten signature...
直筆でめっちゃ書きたいな、
I really want to sign them by hand,
だからフルセット買ってねー。
so please buy the full set!
ちなみに
By the way,
特典ボイスも付いてくるよ！やったー！
it also comes with a bonus voice! Yay!
そんな感じの盛りだくさんな内容なので、
There's so much content packed in here,
ぜひぜひゲットしてください！
so please be sure to get yours!
はい！
Yes!
絶対買ってね、今がチャンスだよ！
Definitely buy it, now's your chance!
そして、もう一つお知らせが
And I have one more
あります！
announcement!
なんと本日、
Today, unbelievably,
この配信の後、
after this stream,
22時15分からメンバー限定で、
at 22:15, for members only,
プチアンコールライブやっちゃいます！
I'll be doing a mini encore live!
イェーイ！
Yay!
メンバー限定配信では、なんと
In the members-only stream, I'll perform
アンコール曲と、
the encore song,
今回のステージを
and introduce the stage
もっとね、近い距離で紹介していきたいなと思います。
from a much closer distance.
可愛いスクショとか、
We can take cute screenshots,
ちょっとイチャイチャしたりとか、
flirt a little,
楽しんでもらえたらいいなと思ってるので、
and I hope you all have a good time.
ぜひぜひメンバー登録の
So, for those who haven't
まだの人は、
joined the membership yet,
忘れずにね！
don't forget to!
今だよ！
Now's the time!
ピース！
Peace!
はい、ということで
Alright, and with that,
それでは、
well then,
アキロゼ生誕祭2023、
Akirose Birthday Festival 2023,
ありがとうございましたー！
thank you all so much!
みんなのおかげで最高の誕生日になりました！ありがとう！
Thanks to everyone, it was the best birthday ever! Thank you!
それでは、
And now,
またねー！
see you later!
メンバーの人、
To the members,
限定配信の準備だー！
get ready for the exclusive stream!
まだの人、
If you aren't one yet,
今だぞー！
now's your chance!
うわー！
Whoa!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
はい！それでは
Yes! And now,
今回メインキャストを務めてくれたメンバーを
let me once again introduce the members
改めて紹介していきたいと思います。
who served as our main cast.
まずは、カカシ役をやってくれた
First, the one who played the Scarecrow,
尾丸ポルカちゃんです！
Omaru Polka-chan!
はい！
Hi!
はい、カカシ役をやりました、
Yes, I played the Scarecrow!
尾丸ポルカです！
I'm Omaru Polka!
どうもありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
イェーイ！
Yay!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
OMARU POLKA
すごいね 緊張したっていうか なんか いつもとさ ね 違うじゃん
It was amazing. I mean, I was nervous... but it was different from usual, wasn't it?
そう うん それでもあの 楽しくやらせていただきました ありがとうございました
Right. Yeah. Still, I really had a lot of fun performing. Thank you very much.
いや 皆様も 本当にありがとうございました
And to everyone watching, thank you so much too!
はい ありがとうございます ポルポル
Yes, thank you very much, Pol-Pol!
最初にこの曲を聞いて もう役柄的にも カカシとピエロの持つ 独特の哀愁だったりとか
When I first heard this song, in terms of the role, the unique melancholy of the Scarecrow and the Clown...
雰囲気がね もうポルカ そのまんま バッチリはまってたって感じでした
...and the overall vibe felt like it fit Polka perfectly.
本当に一緒にやってくれてありがとう 楽しかった
Thank you so much for doing this with me. It was fun!
はい ということでありがとうございました 改めてアキちゃんお誕生日おめでとうございます
Alright, thank you very much. Once again, happy birthday, Aki-chan!
そして皆様もありがとうございました あと他のキャスト陣の挨拶 これからかな
And thank you to everyone as well. Next up are the greetings from the other cast members, I guess?
よし じゃあ行ってきます カカシだよーん あーそれ ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょん
Alright, off I go! It's the Scarecrow~ Hop, hop, hop, hop!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
HAKUI KOYORI
続いては 本場サバンナ出身のライオン…じゃなくてコヨーテだけど
Next up is the lion from the heart of the savannah... well, she's actually a coyote, but...
今日はライオン妹役をやってくれた 博衣こよりちゃんです コンこよー！
...it's Hakui Koyori-chan, who played the role of the younger lion sister today! Kon-Koyo!
はーい ライオン兄弟役をやりました 博衣こよりです イェーイ！
Hi! I played the role of the lion siblings! It's Hakui Koyori! Yay!
あーもう去年のアキ先輩の 3Dミュージカルを拝見した時に めちゃめちゃ感動して
Ah, when I watched Aki-senpai's 3D musical last year, I was so moved!
こよりミュージカル大好きなので アキ先輩にすごい長文の感想を送っちゃったぐらいだったので
I love musicals so much that I sent Aki-senpai a really long message with my thoughts back then.
今年出られて めちゃめちゃ嬉しかったです 楽しかった！ありがとうございました
I was so happy to be able to participate this year. It was so much fun! Thank you very much!
いやー こちらこそ一緒にやってくれて本当にありがとう
No, thank you so much for doing this with me too!
ミュージカルが好きって言ってくれてたし もうこよちゃんとはね いつかやりたいと思ってたから
You said you liked musicals, and I've always wanted to do something with Koyo-chan someday...
今回できて めっちゃ嬉しいです
...so I'm really glad we could do it this time!
それにサバンナの背景も合いすぎてね なんだったら実家感もあったね
And the savannah background suited you so well, it almost felt like home, didn't it?
いや 本当に可愛くて最強でした ありがとう
You were seriously cute and just the best. Thank you!
うわー 嬉しいです 本当にアキ先輩お誕生日おめでとうございます
Wow, that makes me so happy. Happy birthday once again, Aki-senpai!
一緒にやらせていただいて ありがとうございました！それでは！
Thank you so much for letting me perform with you! Goodbye!
SHISHIRO BOTAN
続いて ライオン兄役をやってくれた ホロライブのホワイトライオン 獅白ぼたんちゃんです
Next up is Hololive's white lion, Shishiro Botan-chan, who played the role of the older lion brother!
はい ららーいおん ライオン兄弟役を演じました 獅白ぼたんです
Hi! La-lion! I'm Shishiro Botan, and I played the role of the lion siblings!
ライオンらしく振る舞えたかな？ 楽しかったです よかったー ありがとう
I wonder if I acted lion-like enough? It was fun. I'm glad. Thank you!
雰囲気バッチリ合ってるのは もちろんなんだけど
Of course, the vibe suited you perfectly, but...
ぼたんちゃんの普段見れない ライオンっぽい仕草に 萌えを感じました ありがとう
...I also found the lion-like gestures you don't usually see really adorable. Thank you!
じゃあ最後 メッセージお願いします
Alright, a final message, please.
はい アキ先輩 お誕生日おめでとうございます 参加できて嬉しかったです バイバーイ
Okay! Aki-senpai, happy birthday! I was happy to participate. Bye-bye!
ROBOCOSAN
続いては ロボコさん役をやってくれた ロボット…じゃなくて
Next up is the robot... wait, no, the one who played the role of Roboco-san...
ロボット役をやってくれた ロボ子さんです
...it's Robocosan, who played the role of the robot!
はーい ハローボー ロボット役をやりました ロボ子です ロボだけにね ほら
Hi! Hello-bo! I'm Roboco, and I played the role of the robot. Because I'm a robot, you see?
めちゃめちゃ長くて 難しかったんだけど とても楽しかったです 誘ってくれてありがとう
It was a really long and difficult part, but I had a lot of fun. Thank you for inviting me!
いやー 見事なまでのはまり役 ロボ子さん以外 本当に考えられないという役だったんだけど
Wow, that was such a perfect fit. I really couldn't imagine anyone but Roboco-san in that role.
ダンスもね もうロボットダンスみたいな感じ 難しいというか まあロボットだから簡単か
And the dancing, too! It was like a real robot dance. You said it was hard, but I guess it's easy since you're a robot?
一緒にね 踊れて歌えて 楽しかったー ありがとう
I had so much fun singing and dancing together. Thank you!
はい ありがとう じゃあまたねー
Yes, thank you! See you later!
アキちゃんお誕生日おめでとー！
Aki-chan, happy birthday!
MORI CALLIOPE
そして 最後のメインキャストとして 登場してくれたのは
And appearing as our final main cast member...
超クール 超ロックに決まっていた 西の魔女役の 森カリオペちゃんです
...is Mori Calliope-chan, who was looking super cool and rock-and-roll as the Wicked Witch of the West!
はい ホロライブイングリッシュの 森カリオペです
Hi! I'm Mori Calliope from Hololive English!
I played the part of the Wicked Witch of the West. 西の魔女でした
I played the part of the Wicked Witch of the West. I was the Wicked Witch of the West!
イェーイ ちょっと緊張してたけど 本当に頑張りました よく見てた？ どうだった？
Yay! I was a little nervous, but I really gave it my all. Did you see me? How was it?
めっちゃ最高だったよ 実はこの歌を初めて聞いた時に
It was absolutely awesome! To be honest, when I first heard this song...
もうカリオペちゃんが 高いステージからうわーって 歌う姿を想像してたから
...I immediately pictured Calliope-chan singing her heart out from a high stage.
今回出てくれるってなって 本当にね 嬉しかったんだ
So when I heard you were going to join us, I was truly, truly happy.
カリオペちゃんが登場してからは みんないる大人数パートだったから 特にね わいわいがやがやして 楽しかったね
After Calliope-chan joined in, it was the part with everyone, so it was especially lively and fun, wasn't it?
そうだね ありがとう 超楽しかったね
It really was! Thank you, it was so much fun!
まあまあ アキローズ先輩 Happy Birthday お誕生日おめでとうございます
Anyway, Akirose-senpai, happy birthday! Wishing you a very happy birthday!
今年もよろしくね
I look forward to another great year together!
ありがとう 今年もよろしくね
Thank you! Likewise, let's have a great year!
あの 今年ね 一緒にもっとコラボしてみたいと思いますね
You know, I'd really like to collab with you more this year.
めっちゃ思う！ 嬉しい やろう！
I feel the same way! I'm so happy! Let's do it!
いろんなことに挑戦していこうね 頑張って
Let's try all sorts of new things together! Good luck!
アキ・ローゼンタール
尾丸ポルカ
ロボ子さん
獅白ぼたん
博衣こより
森カリオペ
がうる・ぐら
こぼ・かなえる
アーニャ・メルフィッサ
ハコス・ベールズ
Aki Rosenthal
Omaru Polka
Robocosan
Shishiro Botan
Hakui Koyori
Mori Calliope
Gawr Gura
Kobo Kanaeru
Anya Melfissa
Hakos Baelz
ロゼ隊という宝物に会えたのが
Meeting the treasure known as the Rosetai
アキロゼ最大の幸せ
is Aki-Rose's greatest happiness.
これからも一緒に旅をしてくれる？
Will you continue to journey with me?
Love, Aki